A couple of months ago, I revealed to
you my full process for using AI coding
assistance to build anything fast. But
since then, there have been a few new
MCP servers that have come out. And so,
right now, my workflow for coding
anything with AI revolves around three
core MCP servers. So, I want to cover
those with you right now. But then on
top of that, I also want to do a live
build with you showing you how we can
use these MCP servers together
effectively to build anything. You can
transform any AI coding workflow with
these servers. no matter what you want
to build. So, let's go ahead and dive
into that right now. So, here is the
document outlining my full process for
using AI coding assistance to build
anything. I'll link to this in the
description of this video. I shared this
originally in the other video that I
mentioned. Everything in there is the
same except I've updated section 4 where
I dive into using MCP servers. And so,
these are the three core servers that
I'll cover in this video. There are some
other ones that are worth looking into
as well. These are the ones that I use
no matter what I am building. And the
important thing to note here is that for
each of these servers, there are going
to be multiple options. So, I'll talk
about a couple of these alternatives,
but obviously I want to focus on just
one for each of these three categories.
So, the first kind of MCP server that
you want no matter what is one to bring
external knowledge into your AI coding
assistant for things like library and
tool documentation. So, you have
Superbase, MCP, Pyantic AI, all these
things that you're building with a lot.
these AI coding assistants don't know
them very well. And even though we have
built-in documentation support for some
AI idees like Windsurf and Cursor, it
doesn't always work the best. And so, we
want an MCP server that can essentially
be the rag knowledge base for our AI
coder. And the one that I would highly
recommend using is one that I actually
built myself. It's completely free and
open source. I built it for you
specifically for bringing it into your
AI coding assistance. You can crawl any
website, any documentation and then use
it then as a rag MCP server for your AI
coding assistant and all of the
knowledge that you build as a part of
the server is stored in your own private
superbase. So it's your own knowledge
base that you set up and manage for
yourself. Another good option that I've
covered on my channel previously is
contact 7. Now this isn't going to be
building your own private knowledge base
like this server is but this is another
good option. It's more out of the box.
They have thousands of libraries that
are already ingested in their knowledge
base that you can leverage immediately
again as an MCP server. So that is the
core one that you want. I'm going to be
using this one that I built in this
video here with crawl for AAI. I'll show
you how we can use it to crawl like
Superbase and Pantic AI. Bring that into
our knowledge base. And then the next
kind of server is you want one to help
you manage your database so that when
the AI coding assistant starts a project
for you, not only can it write the code,
but it can also create everything in the
database like new functions, new tables,
and superbase is the primary one that I
use. And so I have this link as well in
the description of the video to the
Superbase MCP server. This can create
tables for you, list your projects that
you have in your Superbase organization.
It can write queries like pretty much
any SQL query you could want. It can do
that as a tool. So it's just a super
powerful way to manage your database
with natural language. So as a part of
your process for building your
application, it can build all the tables
as well. Another one that I mentioned
before on my channel is Neon. That's a
serverless Postgress platform that has a
similar MCP server. And so depending on
the database that you're using,
hopefully there will be an MCP server
that'll help you manage that with
natural language. And I definitely think
we're going in a direction where pretty
much every single database you could use
is going to have an MCP server. So we
might not be there yet. We probably will
in the near future. And then the last
server that I use no matter what is one
to search the web. And typically I use
the Brave MCP server. So I'll have a
link available for this as well. The
Brave API is pretty affordable and it is
very very powerful. It's the kind of web
search that's better than just something
that you would have with ChatGBT or
Claude by itself. It has a very AI
ccentric web search summarizing things
for AI. The way that it pulls
information is just perfect for LLMs.
Usually I'll use this kind of in tandem
with my RAG MCP server. So I'll look in
my knowledge base, but then also search
the web for supplemental resources. Like
sometimes there'll be documentation that
wasn't included in the knowledge base or
maybe there's like community forum posts
that provide examples similar to what I
want to build. And then the Brave MCP
server will help me find that. And if
you want to bring these three MCP
servers into your own AI coding
workflows, which I would highly
recommend doing, then the links that I
have in the description to each of these
also have very detailed instructions.
Like for the crawl for AI rag MCP server
that I built in the readme, I made sure
to walk you through everything as far as
installing, setting up the project,
getting your database configured and
ready to crawl websites and put in your
knowledge base. You can take care of all
that just reading through this step by
step. And then for Brave, you just have
to create your API key and they have
instructions for how you'll set this up
in Cloud Desktop or Windsurf or Cursor,
whatever that might be. And then for
Superbase, it's the same kind of deal.
And the configuration is generally going
to look very, very similar between these
different MCP servers. And so going into
my own Windsurf here, I have the
configuration set up. And the way that I
get to that, by the way, I'll just show
you really quickly. So when I'm in the
cascade mode on the right hand side, you
just have to click on the hammer icon
for MCP servers and then click on
configure and that'll open up this JSON
file for the MCP configuration. And
there's going to be something very
similar for cursor or rue code or client
no matter what AI IDE you are using.
You'll have something like this where
you can add each of the servers
individually. And all these servers are
completely free by the way. So this is
my crawl for AI one. Once you follow the
instructions and you have the server
running on SSE in a terminal, you can
then cook into it just like this. And
then for the Brave search, we're just
pulling this through MPX. The only thing
we need to set up beforehand here is our
Brave API key. And there is a very
generous free tier with Brave. And so
that's why you can get started for free
with Brave. Even though there are paid
plans, I'm still not paying anything for
when I'm using it right here. And then
for Superbase, they also have a very
generous free tier that you can spin up
an instance, have that running
indefinitely, and so you can use this
also without paying anything. The only
thing you have to set up here is your
access token. And in the read me that I
link you to, there's instructions for
getting this set up as well. So very
easy to get all these configured. Once
you have that all configured, you just
have to save here, go back into our
configuration, and click on refresh. And
then that'll load the MCP servers and
you can see all the tools that are
exposed from each of these servers and
the descriptions for them as well. So we
can take a look at everything that our
AI coding assistant is now able to do
with these tools. And so we're giving
superpowers to our AI coders. Now we can
dive into using these all together to
build something from scratch, leveraging
all these to do something that we
definitely couldn't do very easily
without them. The sponsor of today's
video is Datab Button, the AI app
builder for businesses. I've been trying
it out the past few weeks, and I've been
seriously impressed just how much of the
development life cycle DataButton takes
care of for you. Like they say in their
homepage, your hunt for a CTO ends here
because it takes care of everything from
just starting your project all the way
to deploying it. When you first begin a
project, you can start by describing
what you want to build, giving specific
requirements. You can even give
inspiration as well like screenshots
from other web pages and then you can
hook in your integrations like for
authentication, your database, what you
want for payments and then storage as
well. And then you can get started and
the data button agent will go ahead and
start creating a full plan with all the
tasks listed out that it's going to
knock down one by one. We have our
preview so we can see what it's
currently built so far and then we can
interact with our agent on the right
hand side where we provide any feedback
or additional tasks we wanted to do. we
can kick off each individual task and
it'll ask for certain things like our
API keys as it sets up superbase and
stripe getting all those integrations
ready for us and this takes care of the
front end and the back end so you can
deploy agents and APIs behind the scenes
as well and then deploy it all together
once your project is done this takes
care of everything that's why they say
that you don't need a CTO anymore data
button really is a gamecher for lean
businesses that are looking to leverage
AI to compete with companies that are 10
times their size. So, I'll have a link
in the description to data button. It's
free to get started. You can check it
out and see how you can use it to really
build any app that you need for your
business. All right, here we go. Now, it
is time to build. So, we're going to be
leveraging my full process for using AI
coding assistance. I already have some
of the things set up based on this
process. So, I'll show you what that
looks like right now. Then, I'll show
you specifically how I'm going to be
prompting the AI coding assistant to
leverage these different MCP servers.
and then we'll see it in action as well.
And so the first thing is I have my wind
surf rule set up which by the way the
way you get to that is you just go to
additional options in the top right and
go to manage memories and then you can
create global or workspace rules. So I
created some workspace rules here
telling it how to leverage my planning
and task files how to use the crawl for
AI MCP server all that highle direction
that I don't necessarily want to prompt
it to do every single time but I want it
to follow this as its golden rules. And
then I also have my planning file which
I can preview this for you really
quickly just so you can see what this
looks like. So I use claw desktop to
help me make this. Just giving me an
overview of my project and the different
components that I want to build out so
that the AI coding assistant can
reference this and just know what I
really want it to build. So I don't have
to be extremely specific within my
prompt when I actually kick off the
build of this agent that I'm making
here. And so what we are building here
as our live demo is a rag AI agent with
Pantic AI and Superbase. And so we're
going to have this local folder that we
can put files into. It'll automatically
ingest that into our Superbase knowledge
base and then we'll have a simple
streamlet interface for us to interact
with the agent and ask questions about
our knowledge base. So it's a very
simple example, still something we care
about though. I mean rag AI agents are
just so important. And so that's why
we're going to build one right now. And
then I also have my task file with all
of the individual tasks that we want our
agent to look here. and knock these off
one by one and then come back and update
when these tasks are complete. And so
again, everything that I've already
covered in my previous video on my full
process, I have that all set up so that
now we can just dive right into
prompting our AI coding assistant to get
started with this build for us. And so
I'll show you I have the prompt prepared
already. So I'll start at the top,
explain everything really quickly, then
we'll see it in action. So I'm just
starting by saying that I want to build
a simple rag AI agent with padantic AI
and superbase telling it to read the
planning and task files at first as
well. And I do specify in the global
rules to do this, but I'm just really
making sure that it handles this right
now. And then I just describe the
different components that I want for my
AI agent. And I do go into more detail
in the planning and task files for this
as well. So just giving the more higher
level instructions right here. And then
one really powerful thing for using AI
coding assistants in general is to give
examples whenever you can. And so for
the Streamlit user interface
specifically to interact with our agent,
I've seen in the past that AI coding
assistants don't always handle this the
best. And so something that I'm doing
here is I'm giving it an example of a
streaming interface that I've made in
the past specifically to work with
Pyantic AI agents. And so I'm
referencing it like this in windsurf so
it can analyze this file and see exactly
how it's going to build this interface
for me for this agent. So that's just
another gem that I wanted to drop really
quickly for you there. Using examples is
so so powerful. And then I do yet
another example here. So I have the SQL
already prepared for a different project
where I created a rag AI agent. So it
can use this as a reference as well
while it is using the superbase MCP
server to create everything for me in
Superbase for this agent specifically.
And that's why I tell it here. I tell it
to use the Superbase MCP server to
create the necessary database tables.
Make sure I have the extension enabled
for rag and then using this as an
example. And then I continue with the
other two servers. So using crawl for AI
to get the documentation for Pantic AI
and Superbase. I already have all of
that crawled. And so I just had a
separate request where I'm like, hey,
here is the page for podent AI crawl all
those docs. And here's the same thing
for superbase. So I did that already.
Now it has that documentation available.
So just perform the rag queries and then
also use the Brave MCP server like I
mentioned earlier just as kind of like a
supplemental resource for our
knowledgebased lookups because sometimes
when you search the internet you'll find
things like forum posts that have
examples for something like what you're
trying to build. things that can go in
tandem with what we've retrieved from
our superbase knowledge base. So using
these two servers together and then I'm
also very explicit here telling it to
make sure that it uses these servers at
the very start of the process so it has
all the documentation before it tries to
write any code. We don't want it to look
up the documentation after writing all
the code because then it never is really
leveraging it. And so with that we can
now send in this request and see it in
action. And so the first thing that
it'll do because we instruct it to do so
in the prompt in the global rules is to
check our planning and task documents.
And so there we go. It's looking at
planning. Now it's looking at tasks. And
then pretty soon here because we told it
to do it early on, it should start using
our MCP server. So first it's looking at
these examples that we gave, which is
good. I want it to do that as well. Now
here we go. Now we're hitting the
perform rag query endpoint of our MCP
tool getting some of that documentation
for Pyantic AI and it's searching
multiple different times with different
queries. this is exactly what I want it
to do to make sure it has a very
overarching view of everything that it
has to know to implement this agent for
me and then also leveraging the brave
MCP server getting some examples with
integrating superbase and um pyantic AI
together and that's a really powerful
thing in general is a lot of times the
knowledge base will give you here's how
to use this specific library but then
the brave search can tell you how to use
these libraries together. So, yet
another reason that we want to use both
of these tools in tandem. And so, boom,
it's done with all the knowledge lookup.
Now, it's going to update the tasks and
it's going to start creating the readme.
It'll go through the rest of the process
here. And this is going to take a few
good minutes here to build everything
out. And so, what I'll do here is pause
and come back once it has the first
version of my agent complete. And boom,
there we go. It created the full AI
agent for us. It created a readme that
describes the entire project structure.
Look at how many files it built for us.
Making really a full AI agent
application here with the rag pipeline,
the agent and everything. We can take a
look at these individual files. We have
the podantic AI agent. We've got our
dependencies and we have the definition
of the agent itself. This is looking
like really really clean code. We have
our prompts. We have our tools for rag.
We've got everything for actually
processing documents that we upload in a
local folder. Bringing that into our
superbase. We have all the tests as well
because I instructed it to write tests
in our workspace rules. We have our user
interface that we can clearly see that
like this is inspired by the example
that I gave earlier. I mean maybe you
don't know that as much as me because
I've used that example in the past, but
yeah, this is looking really really
good. And then one little glitch here is
it made a brand new task file. So it
wasn't perfect. And I think there are a
couple of bugs that I'll have to fix up
here, but still it did a really really
good job getting me started. I've got my
example environment variables. So, it
tells me everything that I have to set
up with instructions to run everything
in the read me. Like, this feels like a
full software engineer built this out.
Like, I'm really really impressed. And
so, now what I'm going to do is accept
all these changes. I'm going to get
everything set up off camera. There's
probably a couple of iterations that
I'll have to make to make this like
really working. And so, I'll explain all
of that after I do it, too. But, yeah,
let me take care of that now. Then, I'll
show you a full demo with this AI agent
that was created for us so fast. All
right. So, there were a few things that
I had to do to make this in tip-top
shape for us. The first thing is even
though I told it in the first prompt to
use the Superbase MCP server to create
my tables for me, it didn't actually do
that. And AI coding assistants are kind
of unpredictable. Sometimes you have to
reask them to do certain things for you.
So, I did that here. We can see that now
it used the apply migration tool to
create everything with this query that
we can see right here. And then going
into my superbase, I'll actually go to
the table right now. I now have this rag
pages table where we have ID, URL, chunk
number, the embeddings. That's what we
actually use for rag. So, we're good
with the table now. And then there were
some issues around how it embedded the
documents that I would upload to the
interface. So, I had to fix that as
well. Nothing that was related to
Superbase or Pyantic AI. So, it
leveraged the documentation effectively.
Like it actually had zero errors for
anything related to padantic AI like in
our agent here. And then for Superbase,
like when it actually creates the
embeddings and ingests those into our
database. So this whole setup script
that creates this client with all of our
functions to do all of our inserts and
lookups like all of this was perfect
code which is super cool. So I just had
to fix some things with mostly the
chunker and then just the way that it
ingested. So I don't want to get into
the details of all that right now. It's
not very important. But now I have the
interface up and running. Take a look at
this. So I have this streamlight
interface. Let me zoom in on this for
you just a little bit here so you can
see it really well. Now I can browse my
files and I can upload text or PDF
files. Those are the two types that I'm
supporting right now. And so I just have
this fake company overview generated by
Claude that I'm going to use as my mini
knowledge base for this simple example.
So I'll go ahead and upload this and
it'll tell me that it's processing this
file. It's creating all those embeddings
and inserting it into Superbase for me.
And boom, there we go. All documents are
processed. We got five chunks for this
file. We now have one document in our
knowledge base. Now going back to my
table. There we go. All right, we have
our five chunks here. Take a look at
that. This is so cool. And then now I
can talk to my agent or first I can even
show you like if I refresh my page,
it'll now say like, "Yep, you have one
document in your knowledge base." And so
now I can just send a basic message to
the agent just like, "Hello." All right,
there we go. We even have the text
streaming. So it typed it out in like
typewriter style. Super cool. Now I can
ask it a question where it has to
leverage my knowledge base. And I know
this is super basic right now, but I
just wanted to show this at a high
level. uh more focusing on my process
for using these MCP servers. But yeah,
just to show you really quick, I'll say
uh give me an overview of the company.
All right, so we'll watch it perform
rags. So it's going to take a little bit
longer now because it's going to search
my knowledge base. And boom, there we
go. An overview of the company.
Neuroverse Studios, founded in 2022.
Let's go check that really quick. So
yeah, Neuroverse Studios. Yep, founded
in 2022. All right. So, it's leveraging
our knowledge base and it's such a
simple example, but it's just so cool
that I only had to iterate like 20
minutes off camera. So, basically in
like less than an hour, I created this
full application using these three core
MCP servers to guide the entire process
for knowledge, web search, and also
setting up my database for me. I had to
do nothing in Superbase, and this was
all created for me, including the
function under the hood that's used for
rag. So, very, very cool stuff. So, I'll
have a link in the description to this
full example if you want to play around
with it yourself. The main focus though
was how we could start this project
using our three core MCP servers to get
our feet on the ground running. I'd also
highly recommend checking out my
previous video on my full AI coding
assistant process. And also, if you're
interested in taking your AI skills to
the next level, definitely check out
Dynamis.ai. It's my early AI adopter
community that I started recently for
people like you to level up your AI game
to transform your career or business.
And so with that, if you appreciated
this content and you're looking forward
to more things AI coding and AI agents,
I would really appreciate a like and a
subscribe. And with that, I will see you
in the next